<topics>
<top>

<num>401 </num>
<title> foreign minorities, Germany </title>

<desc> Description: 
What language and cultural differences impede the integration 
of foreign minorities in Germany?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will focus on the causes of the lack of
integration in a significant way; that is, the mere mention of
immigration difficulties is not relevant.  Documents that discuss
immigration problems unrelated to Germany are also not relevant.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>402 </num>
<title> behavioral genetics </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is happening in the field of behavioral genetics,
the study of the relative influence of genetic
and environmental factors on an individual's behavior
or personality?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents describing genetic or environmental factors relating
to understanding and preventing substance abuse and addictions
are relevant.  Documents pertaining to attention deficit disorders
tied in with genetics are also relevant, as are genetic disorders 
affecting hearing or muscles.  The genome project is relevant
when tied in with behavior disorders (i.e., mood disorders,
Alzheimer's disease). 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>403 </num>
<title> osteoporosis </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find information on the effects of the dietary intakes
of potassium, magnesium and fruits and vegetables as
determinants of bone mineral density in elderly men
and women thus preventing osteoporosis (bone decay). 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document may include one or more of the
dietary intakes in the prevention of osteoporosis.
Any discussion of the disturbance of nutrition and
mineral metabolism that results in a decrease in 
bone mass is also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>404 </num>
<title> Ireland, peace talks </title>

<desc> Description: 
How often were the peace talks in Ireland delayed
or disrupted as a result of acts of violence?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any interruptions to the peace process not directly
attributable to acts of violence are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>405 </num>
<title> cosmic events </title>

<desc> Description: 
What unexpected or unexplained cosmic events or
celestial phenomena, such as radiation and 
supernova outbursts or new comets, have been detected?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
New theories or new interpretations concerning 
known celestial objects made as a result of new 
technology are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>406 </num>
<title> Parkinson's disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is being done to treat the symptoms of 
Parkinson's disease and keep the patient 
functional as long as possible?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document identifies a drug or treatment 
program utilized in patient care and provides 
an indication of success or failure.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>407 </num>
<title> poaching, wildlife preserves </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is the impact of poaching on 
the world's various wildlife preserves? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must discuss poaching in wildlife
preserves, not in the wild itself.  Also deemed relevant
is evidence of preventive measures being taken by local
authorities.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>408 </num>
<title> tropical storms </title>

<desc> Description: 
What tropical storms (hurricanes and typhoons) have
caused significant property damage and loss of life?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The date of the storm, the area affected, and the extent of 
damage/casualties are all of interest.  Documents that describe
the damage caused by a tropical storm as "slight", "limited", or
"small" are not relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>409 </num>
<title> legal, Pan Am, 103 </title>

<desc> Description: 
What legal actions have resulted from the destruction
of Pan Am Flight 103 over Lockerbie, Scotland, on
December 21, 1988?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents describing any charges, claims, or fines 
presented to or imposed by any court or tribunal are
relevant, but documents that discuss charges made in
diplomatic jousting are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>410 </num>
<title> Schengen agreement </title>

<desc> Description: 
Who is involved in the Schengen agreement to eliminate border
controls in Western Europe and what do they hope to accomplish?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will contain any information about the
actions of signatories of the Schengen agreement such as:
measures to eliminate border controls (removal of traffic
obstacles, lifting of traffic restrictions); implementation
of the information system data bank that contains unified
visa issuance procedures; or strengthening of border controls
at the external borders of the treaty area in exchange for 
free movement at the internal borders.  Discussions of border 
crossovers for business purposes are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>411 </num>
<title> salvaging, shipwreck, treasure </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find information on shipwreck salvaging: the
recovery or attempted recovery of treasure from
sunken ships.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide information on
the actual locating and recovery of treasure; 
on the technology which makes possible the discovery,
location and investigation of wreckages which 
contain or are suspected of containing treasure; or
on the disposition of the recovered treasure. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>412 </num>
<title> airport security </title>

<desc> Description: 
What security measures are in effect or are proposed
to go into effect in airports?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document could identify a specific airport
and describe the security measures already in effect 
or proposed for use at that airport.  Relevant items
could also describe a failure of security that was
cited as a contributing cause of a tragedy which came 
to pass or which was later averted.  Comparisons between
and among airports based on the effectiveness of the
security of each are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>413 </num>
<title> steel production </title>

<desc> Description: 
What are new methods of producing steel?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will discuss the processes adapted
by entrepreneurs who have organized so-called "minimills"
and are producing steel by methods which differ from
the old blast furnace method of production.  Documents 
that identify the new companies, the problems they have
have encountered, and/or their successes or failures in
the national and international markets are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>414 </num>
<title> Cuba, sugar, exports </title>

<desc> Description: 
How much sugar does Cuba export and which
countries import it?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide information
regarding Cuba's sugar trade.  Sugar production
statistics are not relevant unless exports
are mentioned explicitly.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>415 </num>
<title> drugs, Golden Triangle </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is known about drug trafficking in the
"Golden Triangle", the area where Burma,
Thailand and Laos meet?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will discuss drug
trafficking in the Golden Triangle,
including organizations that produce or
distribute the drugs; international efforts
to combat the traffic; or the quantities of
drugs produced in the area.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>416 </num>
<title> Three Gorges Project </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is the status of The Three Gorges Project?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide the projected
date of completion of the project, its estimated
total cost, or the estimated electrical output of
the the finished project.  Discussions of the
social, political, or ecological impact of the
project are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>417 </num>
<title> creativity </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find ways of measuring creativity.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant items include definitions of creativity,
descriptions of characteristics associated with
creativity, and factors linked to creativity. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>418 </num>
<title> quilts, income </title>

<desc> Description: 
In what ways have quilts been used to generate income?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents mentioning quilting books, quilting classes,
quilted objects, and museum exhibits of quilts are all relevant.  
Documents that discuss AIDs quilts are irrelevant, unless 
there is specific mention that the quilts are being used 
for fundraising.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>419 </num>
<title> recycle, automobile tires </title>

<desc> Description: 
What new uses have been developed for old
automobile tires as a means of tire recycling?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must show advantageous uses of
recycled tires, such as:  destructive distillation of 
scrap rubber for valuable chemicals, reef building
for fish habitats, filler or binder in asphalt
roadway mixes, and burning in a controlled 
environment for heat generation.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>420 </num>
<title> carbon monoxide poisoning </title>

<desc> Description: 
How widespread is carbon monoxide poisoning on 
a global scale?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will contain data on
what carbon monoxide poisoning is, symptoms,
causes, and/or prevention.  Advertisements for
carbon monoxide protection products or services 
are not relevant.  Discussions of auto emissions
and air pollution are not relevant even though
they can contain carbon monoxide.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>421 </num>
<title> industrial waste disposal </title>

<desc> Description: 
How is the disposal of industrial waste being accomplished
by industrial management throughout the world? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss the disposal, storage, or management
of industrial waste---both standard and hazardous---are
relevant.  However, documents that discuss disposal or
storage of nuclear or radioactive waste, or the illegal
shipment or dumping of waste to avoid legal disposal
methods are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>422 </num>
<title> art, stolen, forged</title>

<desc> Description: 
What incidents have there been of stolen or forged art?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Instances of stolen or forged art in any media are relevant. 
Stolen mass-produced things, even though they might be 
decorative, are not relevant (unless they are mass-
produced art reproductions). Pirated software, music, movies, 
etc. are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>423 </num>
<title> Milosevic, Mirjana Markovic </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find references to Milosevic's wife, Mirjana Markovic.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any mention of the Serbian president's wife is
relevant, even if she is not named.  She may be referred to
by her nickname, Mira.  A general mention of his family, 
without specifying his wife, is not relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>424 </num>
<title> suicides </title>

<desc> Description: 
Give examples of alleged suicides that aroused suspicion
of the death actually being murder.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The intent of this query is to find criminal murders that 
are being disguised as suicide, but assisted suicides done
out of compassion would be relevant if someone refers to 
them as murder.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>425 </num>
<title> counterfeiting money </title>

<desc> Description: 
What counterfeiting of money is being done in
modern times?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents must cite actual instances
of counterfeiting.   Anti-counterfeiting measures by
themselves are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>426 </num>
<title> law enforcement, dogs </title>

<desc> Description: 
Provide information on the use of dogs worldwide for 
law enforcement purposes.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant items include specific information on the
use of dogs during an operation.  Training of dogs
and their handlers are also relevant.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>427</num>
<title> UV damage, eyes </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find documents that discuss the damage ultraviolet (UV)
light from the sun can do to eyes.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will discuss diseases that result
from exposure of the eyes to UV light, treatments
for the damage, and/or education programs that help
prevent damage.  Documents discussing treatment
methods for cataracts and ocular melanoma are relevant
even when a specific cause is not mentioned.  However,
documents that discuss radiation damage from nuclear
sources or lasers are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>428 </num>
<title> declining birth rates </title>

<desc> Description: 
Do any countries other than the U.S. and China have
a declining birth rate? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document will name a country other than the U.S. 
or China in which the birth rate fell from the rate of the
previous year.  The decline need not have occurred in more
than the one preceding year.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>429 </num>
<title> Legionnaires' disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify outbreaks of Legionnaires' disease.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss a specific outbreak
of Legionnaires' disease.  Documents that address prevention of
or cures for the disease without citing a specific case are 
not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>430 </num>
<title> killer bee attacks </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify instances of attacks on humans by Africanized 
(killer) bees.  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents must cite a specific instance of a human
attacked by killer bees.  Documents that note migration patterns
or report attacks on other animals are not relevant unless they
also cite an attack on a human.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>431 </num>
<title> robotic technology </title>

<desc> Description: 
What are the latest developments in robotic technology?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will contain information on 
current applications of robotic technology.  Discussions
of robotics research or simulations of robots are
not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>432 </num>
<title> profiling, motorists, police </title>

<desc> Description: 
Do police departments use "profiling" to stop motorists?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will report or discuss police department 
criteria for identifying motorists considered likely to be
carrying contraband.  Documents discussing the detention of
individuals by foreign security forces are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>433 </num>
<title> Greek, philosophy, stoicism </title>

<desc> Description: 
Is there contemporary interest in the Greek
philosophy of stoicism?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Actual references to the philosophy or philosophers, 
productions of Greek stoic plays, and new "stoic" 
artistic productions are all relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>434 </num>
<title> Estonia, economy </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is the state of the economy of Estonia?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that give concrete economic information
such as economic statistics, entering economic unions
and treaties, or monetary performance are relevant,
as are discussions of economic issues such as 
transportation or pollution.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>435 </num>
<title> curbing population growth </title>

<desc> Description: 
What measures have been taken worldwide and what 
countries have been effective in curbing
population growth?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must describe an actual case in which 
population measures have been taken and their results are known.
The reduction measures must have been actively pursued;
that is, passive events such as disease or famine
involuntarily reducing the population are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>436 </num>
<title> railway accidents </title>

<desc> Description: 
What are the causes of railway accidents throughout
the world? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document provides data on railway accidents
of any sort (i.e., locomotive, trolley, streetcar) where
either the railroad system or the vehicle or pedestrian
involved caused the accident.  Documents that discuss
railroading in general, new rail lines, new technology
for safety, and safety and accident prevention 
are not relevant, unless an actual accident is described.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>437 </num>
<title> deregulation, gas, electric </title>

<desc> Description: 
What has been the experience of residential utility
customers following deregulation of gas and electric?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss privatization of government-
owned utilities alone are not relevant.  Also, not
relevant are documents that discuss the deregulation 
of utilities for commercial customers.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>438 </num>
<title> tourism, increase </title>

<desc> Description: 
What countries are experiencing an increase in
tourism?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will name a country that
has experienced an increase in tourism.
The increase must represent the nation as a whole
and tourism in general, not be restricted to only
certain regions of the country or to some specific
type of tourism (e.g., adventure travel).  Documents
discussing only projected increases are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>439 </num>
<title> inventions, scientific discoveries </title>

<desc> Description: 
What new inventions or scientific discoveries have been
made?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The word "new" in the description is defined as occurring
in the 1990s.  Documents that indicate a "recent" 
invention or scientific discovery are considered relevant.
Discoveries made in astronomy or any scientific discoveries
that are not patentable are not relevant.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>440 </num>
<title> child labor </title>

<desc> Description: 
What steps are being taken by governments or corporations 
to eliminate abuse of child labor?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document identifies an action taken by either 
a private commercial corporation or governmental organization 
to reduce or eliminate the use of child labor in manufacturing 
operations.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>441 </num>
<title> Lyme disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
How do you prevent and treat Lyme disease?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss current prevention and
treatment techniques for Lyme disease are
relevant.  Reports of research on new
treatments of the disease are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>442 </num>
<title> heroic acts </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find accounts of selfless heroic acts by individuals or 
small groups for the benefit of others or a cause.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will contain a description of specific
acts.  General statements concerning heroic acts are not
relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>443 </num>
<title> U.S., investment, Africa </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is the extent of U.S. (government and private)
investment in sub-Saharan Africa?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
All references to U.S. Governmental and private assistance
to sub-Saharan Africa are relevant.  Documents discussing
contributions by reason of U.S. membership in international
aid organizations are also relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>444 </num>
<title> supercritical fluids</title>

<desc> Description: 
What are the potential uses for supercritical fluids
as an environmental protection measure?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must indicate that the 
fluid involved is achieved by a process of pressurization
producing the supercritical fluid.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>445</num>
<title> women clergy </title>

<desc> Description: 
What other countries besides the United States are considering 
or have approved women as clergy persons?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must indicate either a country 
where a woman has been installed as clergy or a country
that is considering such an installation.  The clergy position
must be as church pastor rather than some other church capacity
(e.g., nun or choir member). 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>446 </num>
<title> tourists, violence </title>

<desc> Description: 
Where are tourists likely to be subjected to
acts of violence causing bodily harm or death?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must contain accounts of known 
harm to tourists.  Evidence of single, isolated
incidents are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>447 </num>
<title> Stirling engine </title>

<desc> Description: 
What new developments and applications are there
for the Stirling engine?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any discussion of new developments and applications of the
Stirling engine (also known as the Stirling cycle) are relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>448 </num>
<title> ship losses </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify instances in which weather was a main or contributing
factor in the loss of a ship at sea.  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any ship loss due to weather is relevant, either in international
or coastal waters.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>449 </num>
<title> antibiotics ineffectiveness </title>

<desc> Description: 
What has caused the current ineffectiveness of
antibiotics against infections and what is
the prognosis for new drugs?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss the reasons or 
causes for the ineffectiveness of current antibiotics.
Relevant documents may also include efforts by pharmaceutical
companies and federal government agencies to find new cures, 
updating current testing phases, new drugs being tested,
and the prognosis for the availability of new and effective
antibiotics. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>450 </num>
<title> King Hussein, peace </title>

<desc> Description: 
How significant a figure over the years was the late
Jordanian King Hussein in furthering peace in the 
Middle East?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must include mention of Israel;
King Hussein himself as opposed to other Jordanian
officials; discussion of the King's on-going, previous 
or upcoming efforts; and efforts pertinent to the peace 
process, not merely Jordan's relationship with other 
middle-east countries or the U.S. 
</narr>
</top>
</topics>
